[Music]
Sir, today at Hotstocks our focus is on
a particular news rather than a particular segment.
Sir, the news flow is
speculating a bit about the market,
I want to discuss it with you.
Although it is highly likely.  It
is highly anticipated that this will also be seen happening.
You know, as expected,
interest rates will be cut by half a percent, repo rate will be cut.  A
similar trend is now emerging regarding third
party motor insurance premium.
Now you will say that I
track the auto sector, so similar
news is being presented to me again and again.
Talked about India Motors and other auto stocks.  Now Sir, it is a coincidence
that you are present with us today and we are
discussing all these things.  Where
your hold is also very strong.  Your
interest is also very high.  Now it is believed
Sir that the
third party premiums for motor vehicles
may be increased in two to three weeks.  Such
news is coming out quoting news reports.  The
Ministry of Road
Transport and Highways is considering increasing the premium for FY26, the
current financial year,
which may happen in the next two to three weeks.
Now IRDAI, which
is the regulator of the sector, has itself demanded an increase of 18% in the
third party motor premium on an average
and why is this happening
because if you see in the last 4 years, the
third party insurance premiums have
not been increased, they have not been touched, so
you know, a very fast exercise is being done by these companies that
this third party motor
insurance premium which is mandatory for us,
if you drive any vehicle then it is
mandatory for you to take third party insurance.  Let me present its importance and its
figures before you.
But if we look at it overall, sir, then two-three
companies will be positively impacted by this
because if you look at the total motor premium, then
third party has a big contribution
and
according to the data of F25 that we have, if you look at the total
motor premium, then third party has a
60% share and
if you look at general insurance as a whole, then
third party has almost 19%
contribution.  So, this third
party motor premium, if
seen in itself, matters a lot for the entire industry.
As far as the general insurance industry is concerned, it is
around 20% which is 1/10th of the business. If the increase of 18%,
20%, 25% which is being discussed here, happens, then it will be a
very good thing for these companies and that is
because ICICI LBAD GIT and New India
Insurance, which specifically
operate in this business.  Sir, their TP loss
ratio, TP loss ratio means third
party loss ratio, I will also explain the loss ratio.
Sir, I would also request you to
shed some light on this.   The
third party loss ratio of ICICI
LBA is 64.2%.  69% is of Go Digit and
108% is of New India Insurance.  This
third party loss ratio means
how much premium you pay as a percentage of the
claims you
receive.  So in that sense,
New India Insurance pays more premium
in claims than the premium you collected.  That means it is in loss.
70% is paid by Go Digit and
64% by ICICI LBAT.  That means
they save around 35% of the premium.  Sir,
first of all please tell me whether I have understood this number correctly.
This TP loss ratio is
understood like this and the kind of discussion that is going on now.
What are your expectations sir?
After 4 years, should we assume that the
premiums for third
party motor insurance may increase?   What you
said about TP loss is absolutely correct.
This is what happens when you are selling that
particular policy to your customers in your kitty, the
total premium collection and sir
insurance company also works in the same way
that they collect
insurance premium from their entire client base
and some of them are compensated.
So, usefully, there is
a huge quantum increase in their profitability
and you will see that
this has been a dampener in that particular profitability
and Sir, let me tell you one more reason behind this that the
problem that we are seeing in third party claims,
where are we seeing so much problem, you must have noticed
Sir, no matter how old the vehicle you are
driving, third party insurance has become
mandatory for you.  Well, the second
thing is that Sir, the valuation of other vehicles
or other asset classes which are
covered under utility damage has become
very high.  Now you
see, if your car is 12 years or 15 years old,
you would have paid
your insurance
premium of ₹7 to ₹8000 with a third party,
and after that, if God
forbid you have an accident with an expensive car
and you go for a claim, then there is a
capping in that too, but that
capping also becomes very big, so
definitely this is the thing and Sir, there is one more thing
that the Government of India has made it mandatory that
whether you have comprehensive
insurance or not, it does
not matter much in comparison to your third
party.  So if you are driving a vehicle on the road,
third party
insurance becomes mandatory for you.  And that premium was
extremely low in comparison with the asset
cover that they were getting.  So definitely
you will see this change coming.  The
government is also understanding this.  Everyone
understands that a problem area is
emerging.  And you'll
see this coming as soon as you can.  All these companies of yours, HDFC,
Ago Bajaj Ali, now Bajaj Ali is
no longer there but Bajaj, you, ICIC LBD, which you were just
talking about, and New India Insurance,
you will also see a breather in all these
and you may also see an upside in these.
Sir, we are in agreement with the discussion about
increase in premium, that is you are also
agreeing that the demand of the industry is
absolutely right and the average of 18% that
IRDAI, which is the regulator, has
demanded, is that justified, sir, absolutely,
because you should see one thing, sir, it is a very basic
thing, now as a consumer if I
see it, I will feel that it was
going well, what is the problem, why do I have to do it,
but sir, you should see how much coverage
these people are providing and if you are walking on the road
, it is a public place, you are
walking in it, then there are certain
liabilities which you have to take care of.
And if you have to pay a premium for that, you will have to
pay it.  How long will these companies
handle it?  So according to me, this
particular rerating is correct
and it should happen because sir, whatever
you want to protect,
you should remove the third party insurance today.
Today, if you have a car accident
and a case is filed against you, then sir, you may have to
suffer huge losses.  Third party
coverage is also important and his premium
collection was a bit smoky.  It should be enhanced a little.
Meaning,
I am not doing anything for the insurance company.  I am
not running any campaign for them.  But
sir at the end of the day they will only
protect you well if they are earning well
from you.  If not, then
you may face problems somewhere there also.
So according to me, paying the premium
is mandatory.  Sir, there are three options in this entire
space, ICICI LBA gdit and New India
Insurance. Which one are you eyeing, sir,
which of these stocks or any other,
you know, based on this news flow, where do
you feel there is an opportunity to buy
or money can be made?
Sir, for me the best one
is ICICI and I think
you can definitely keep an eye on ICICI and as
you see this news
maturing completely in it, you will
also be able to see upside.  Ok?  It's perfect.
So in that sense,
if you look at ICICI Low Part in this entire space, a
very good move was seen in this stock on Friday.
So the expectation is that yes, the premiums for
motor third party insurance may
see an increase here.
If this happens then it could be a matter of relief for these companies.  There is
ICICI LBA in that entire space which you
can consider and move here.  What view should I take sir
and how much upset do you think the stock can face
?
Look, Sir, I would like to add one more thing to you
that the way your ICICI LT is moving right now,
it has broken one of its multiple
resistance levels where it was
coming and checking the resistance somewhere and
now if you look at this movement, then it can
very comfortably show you a movement up to ₹218
in this up trend and
in the medium term, as this decision
moves forward,
this particular stock has less power to show you a movement up to ₹2340.
Ok?  So ok.  So
one thing is clear from this entire discussion that the motor third
party insurance premium seems
almost certain to increase.  We will have to
see how much the quantum is.  The regulators are
coming forward and saying that you should make it 18%.  If it has
not happened for 4 years then it is due.
If it happens, it is obvious that if you look at my pocket and
anyone who drives a car, there will be
a burden on them.  It will
affect them.  But
for these companies that provide us services.
Perhaps if we look at it quality wise
or service wise, then
an improvement can definitely be seen.
ICICI LBAD is one of the best picks in this entire space
which can show further upside in the near term till 2108
and beyond.
So
now we end this entire discussion here.  But
ICICI LBRD is one of the good ones, yes sir
please do you want to say something?  Sir,
I would like to add one more thing.  Look, it must have been
202 years since you started driving
and I too have had a little bit of time
behind me.  Sir, you might have noticed one thing that
we have
coverage of Nil Day Insurance in our policy and that is such an
insurance which gives us the
opportunity to drive the car without any worry,
you should pay attention sir, earlier times it was that as soon as
your car reached its second year,
50% depreciation on plastic would definitely be deducted.
80-85% of the iron parts will definitely be cut.  That
means the car would come in the second year
and I felt like now I will take it out on the road.   If
something goes wrong, it will cost me money.
Today, for 10 years, you have been saying boldly
that even if someone insists and goes away, you do
not even feel a frown.  They say no problem, they are
walking on the road and they collide.
Sir, there is nothing to worry about, I am telling you that.
Well, you should talk about engine insurance.
So there is so much pressure on the insurance companies as the
rainy season is about to come.
Who has taken engine insurance.  Of course,
you can go offroading with him.  The
car's engine seized.   The
insurance company people will come.  The poor guy will tow it away.  I will
fix it and leave.
So you are getting the benefit too,
sir.
If I collide with a BMW 7 Series on my motorcycle, I will have to sell my kidney while paying
it.  At least I have
third party insurance
with me which can support me.  So sir, you will have to pay the
premium.  We will definitely have to pay
and its benefit can be
seen in the stock of ICICI LBARD.  With this, let
us wind up this special discussion here.
[Music]